<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Ryan Montville</title>
<link>https://ryanmontville.com/</link>
<description>I made an rss feed because why not. Really just testing this.</description>
<item>
<title>Bee Inspection - A React.js App (March 2023)</title>
<link>https://github.com/RyanMontville/Bee-Inspection</link>
<guid>https://github.com/RyanMontville/Bee-Inspection</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>My parents are bee keepers as a hobby. They wanted to start recording the state of the hives whenever they
            inspect the hive. I have created a web application that they can quickly and easily record the data using
            their phone. The purpose of recording the inspections is to try to find patterns and possibly use the data
            from last year to predict what will happen this year. The app uses Java, SQL, JSON, HTML, CSS, Javascript,
            React.js, and Bootstrap.<a href="https://github.com/RyanMontville/Bee-Inspection">View the Github Repo</a> | <a href="https://ryanmontville.github.io/bee-inspection/">View the Live Demo</a></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Python Maze Generator - A Python App (June 2024)</title>
<link>https://ryanmontville.github.io/pythonmaze/</link>
<guid>https://ryanmontville.github.io/pythonmaze/</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>I wanted to try to use Turtle Graphics to randomly generate mazes using python. I still consider this project a work in progress because I have not yet achieved the level of randomness that I imagined when I started this project. Version 1 creates a grid and randomly draws line on the grid. It almost always is unsolvable. Version 2 draws premade segments than randomly change in size and randomly close off paths. The current version (version 3) takes a word or phrase and generates a maze using the letters as paths.<a href="https://github.com/RyanMontville/pythonmaze/">View the Github Repo</a> | <a href="https://ryanmontville.github.io/pythonmaze/version-three.html">View the Live Demo</a></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>